.\load_gltf.cc


the buffer itself.
the vector of bytes. bufferView and accessor will be used to read it.
convince the compiler that data points to floating point data.
read in the vec3.
the buffer itself.
the vector of bytes. bufferView and accessor will be used to read it.
convince the compiler that data points to floating point data.
read in the vec3.
objVertices.emplace_back(ObjVertex{ glm::vec3(ptr_to_vec3(memoryLocation)) });
the buffer itself.
the vector of bytes. bufferView and accessor will be used to read it.
convince the compiler that data points to floating point data. Move data ptr forward by stride bytes.
read in the vec2.
deal with the fact that the obj format's texcoord.t is inverted, and the base code assumes the obj format.
the buffer itself.
the vector of bytes. bufferView and accessor will be used to read it.
convince the compiler that data points to a particular size of data. Move data ptr forward by stride bytes.
apply parent's transforms to the children
the node's CTM will still contain only the node-local transform.
initialize a TreeNode with no matrix transforms.
apply any individual transforms in order.
There's also a completed matrix transform option, so if the file has that, override the CTM with this new matrix.
if the node has children
construct a new TreeNode that has the child node, and the CTM of the parent
call this function again.
this is a child of some other node.
gltf buffers may have many interleaved buffers, and the main objects that
define what belongs to what are:
Accessors, and Bufferviews
the accessor defines access to which bufferview is being used. 
ByteOffset and count are most important, as well as which bufferview to use
the bufferview refers to a buffer. It also contains:
byteOffset: which byte of the buffer to start reading from
byteLength: how many bytes to read from the buffer, starting from byteOffset
byteStride: Useful for interleaved values. How many bytes are inbetween the start
            of each of the objects referred to by the accessor-bufferview combo.
verify assumption about gltf data
count the maximum number of vertices needed for this model
meshes in scene
shapes in mesh
indices in shape
for (const auto& node : model.nodes) {
    graph.constructCTMTree(model, node, nullptr);
}
 Loop over shapes in the gltf file
the gltf format's individual primitive indices all start from 0. 
This is incompatible with the way the .obj format stores its shape data, where the first index of the next shape starts where the previous shape left off.
To make the format consistent, this adds the previous vertex index number to the shape. 
E.g. if shape 0 has 30, shape 1 has 60 indices, then shape 2's indices will start from 90 instead of 0.
construct the CTM from the node's data.
constructCTM(model, TreeNode(node, mat4(1.0f)));
skip this node if it contains no meshes. This should be pretty rare.
shapes in mesh
only work with triangle data for now.
determine where our data is
assume the gltf files have vertex positions and indices.
add in the amount of vertices we added, so the next shape's index starts where we left off.
optionally find normal data and include it
optionally find texture data and include it

.\load_obj.cc


/ TinyObj index type that can be used in a hash table. 
 Verify assumptions about obj data
 Count the maximum number of vertices needed for this model
 Allocate space for all vertices. 
 Map allows us to avoid duplicating vertices by ignoring combinations of attributes we've already seen. 
 Loop over shapes in the obj file
 Loop over all faces while also iterating over indexing information
 We only know how to work with triangles
 Loop over the three vertices of a triangle. 
 If it exists, copy normal data into the vertex array.
 If it exists, copy texture coordinate data into the vertex array.
 Add shape to MultiShapeGeometry output object
 Add all vertices to output object
 Done

.\load_texture.cc



* contents adapted from https://vulkan-tutorial.com/
* Creative Commons 0 Licensing information: https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/

returns the first available memory type index for a given physicalDevice
load a single texture
the type of this structure
 no structure extending this structure
no access from other queue families, see https://vulkan.lunarg.com/doc/view/1.2.154.1/windows/tutorial/html/03-init_device.html
number of entries in the pQueueFamilyIndices array
set to null if in EXCLUSIVE sharing mode
the path of the image
width of the image
height of the image
the actual number of channels in the raw image
adds an alpha channel to the image for formatting consistency
TODO maybe throw exception here
height, width, channel number
purple
Consider using a fallback texture, like this transparent image. Or bright solid white, depending on the background.
free texture data
free the texture image view, must be done before freeing the image itself
free the texture image
takes a created image (from createImage) and creates an image view from it
for now, use a pretty generic sampler for all textures. Can overload to provide more options, and potentially move a set of common
samplers into the TextureLoader class.
No filtering. Other option is VK_FILTER_LINEAR for bilinear filtering
No filtering, Other option is VK_FILTER_LINEAR for anisotropic filtering
you can query the physical device to check the max available anisotropy, but not enabling it for now.
set to true if you wish to address coordinates from [0,texWidth) and [0, texHeight). False indicates [0,1) on both axes, which is more common.
Used for shadow-mapping
mip-mapping
pipeline barrier

.\main.cc


 Fix MSVC warning about binary compatability
 Include shared_ptr
static initialization problem generates linker error, using global for now
/ Our application class. Pay attention to the member variables defined at the end. 
updates shading based on key holds
records the original shading.
names of the loaded shapefiles.
holds the original state of each of the object's shading layer
/ An wrapped instance of struct WorldInfo made available automatically as uniform data in our shaders.
/ Static variables to be updated by glfw callbacks. 
/ Callback for mousewheel scrolling. Used to zoom the view. 
revert to each object's original layer
observe and apply the current shading layer to all objects
* Keyboard callback:
 *    G: Toggle cursor grabbing. A grabbed cursor makes controlling the view easier.
 *    F, F11: Toggle fullscreen view.
 *    ESC: Close the application

modes start. They are the corresponding enum values, shifted up 1 for use on a keyboard.
modes end
 Not fullscreen. Go fullscreen...
 Fullscreen, go back to windowed.
 Set glfw callbacks
 Initialize uniform variables
 Initialize geometry 
 Initialize shaders
 Initialize graphics pipeline and render setup 
 Run until the application is closed
 Poll for window events, keyboard and mouse button presses, ect...
set shading layers based on polled events
 Update view matrix
 Render the frame 
 Adjust the viewport if window is resized
 Make sure the GPU is done rendering before exiting. 
/ Update view matrix from orbit camera controls 
 If this is the first frame, set delta to zero. 
/ Update perspective matrix
 Vulkan uses a flipped y-axis
 Let base class handle  cleanup.
/ Animate the objects within our scene and then render it. 
 Global time
 Spin the logo in place. 
 Spin the ball opposite direction of logo, above it.
 Spin the cube around above both the logo and the ball.
 move the lantern into the background
position dummy
 Rotate all other objects around the Vulkan logo in the center
 120 degrees
 Tell the GPU to render a frame. 
example of setting diffuse and shininess only
example of default initialization
 loads all .gltf, .glb, and .obj files found in "dir" and its subdirectories into mObjects.
 If you don't want to do this, you have a few options:
 1. don't use this function, and instead manually load the shapefiles of your choosing using the load_x_to_vulkan functions.
 2. Create specific omissions/permissions by modifying the lambda functions.
 3. put any shape files you aren't using in your asset directory into a "junk" folder, and check if the entry.path().string() is equivalent to that junk folder's name
depth first
 Load all shape files. This is what pushes filenames to mObjectNames.
 Create new uniform data for each object
Make a color map. You can either improve on this, or throw it away and use something more sophisticated.
set uniform shading data to colors defined in color map, or to some texture. The key is the name of the file, without the extension.
this is called after all mObjectAnimShades are initialized, which records their initial shading layer for reverting after pressing keybinds 1-5.
Can remove all of the shading layer code if you are not using the debug shader.
 Add objects to the scene along with its uniform data
for each multiShapeObject
for each shape in that object. Change
this keeps track of where in the vector of descriptor sets the particular shape's descriptor set data was inserted into.
the position we will be inserting into in the next iteration of the outer loop.
our insertion helper vector "sets" gets destroyed every loop, hence the +=.
/ Initialize our shaders
 Get the handle representing the GPU. 
 Load the compiled shader code from disk. 
/ Initialize uniform data and bind them.
 Specify the structure of single instance uniforms
 Bind world info uniform data to binding point #0
 Specify the layout for per-object uniform data
 {<binding point>, <structure layout>}
 Transform data on binding point #1
 Blinn-Phong data on binding point #2

.\VulkanGraphicsApp.cc


Vulkan with no extensions requires imageViews to point to a non-null image.
This is why this is called before initializing descriptor sets/layouts, and not during main.
The order in which you create these matters, see TextureLoader::getDescriptorImageInfos()
and its usage in VulkanGraphicsApp:writeDescriptorSets().
Might rework TextureLoader into using a map again, using same naming as main's objects.
The code currently uses array textures, with up to 16 textures per array supported, from what I could find on their minimum support.
TODO add fallback for any graphics devices that don't support array textures (query in device setup)
give the command pool handle to use in submitting vkCmdCopyBufferToImage command, for one-time transfer to GPU memory
 Instances to start with
 Capacity to start with
 sType = 
 pNext = 
 pApplicationName = 
 applicationVersion = 
 pEngineName = 
 engineVersion = 
 apiVersion = 
write an updateDevice for TextureLoader if you want to update textures on-device
sType = 
pNext = 
waitSemaphoreCount = 
pWaitSemaphores = 
swapchainCount = 
pSwapchains = 
pImageIndices = 
pResults = 
 Allocate a command buffer for each in-flight frame extra for transfer operations. 
the background
 Bind vertex buffer for object
 Bind uniforms to graphics pipeline if they exist with correct dynamic offset for this object instance
 Bind index buffer for each shape and issue draw command.
 The previous version of this code bound the index buffer with an offset of
 mMultiShapeObjects[objIdx].getShapeRange(shapeIdx), and left the first index
 of vkCmdDrawIndexed at 0. Now, the whole index buffer is bound, and the first index of the draw
 is offset based on this amount. Now the bind command only has to be run once for each object,
 rather than once for each shape in each object.
command buffer
index buffer
offset
index type
 the dynamic offset argument is equivalent to 
 the index of the shape of the current model, plus all of the shapes that were drawn before it in this render pass. 
 It is used to index into the descriptor set for that particular shape, and bind it before drawing.
command buffer to bind to
pipeline bind point
vkpipelinelayout obj
firstSet
descriptorset count
pDescriptorSets
dynamic offset count
dynamic offsets array
command buffer
index count
instance count
first index
base index within the index buffer
vertex offset
the value added to the vertex index before indexing into the vertex buffer
first instance
instance id of the first instance to draw.
 Create layout from merged set of bindings from both the multi instance and single instance buffers
emplace all of the VkDescriptorBufferInfos.
 sType = 
 pNext = 
 dstSet = 
 dstBinding = 
 dstArrayElement = 
 descriptorCount = 
 descriptorType = 
 pImageInfo = 
 pBufferInfo = 
 pTexelBufferView = 
finally, emplace the VkDescriptorImageInfo.
 sType = 
 pNext = 
 dstSet = 
 dstBinding = 
 dstArrayElement = 
 descriptorCount = 
 descriptorType = 
 pImageInfo = 
 pBufferInfo = 
 pTexelBufferView = 

.\geometry.h


/ glm doesn't support contruction from pointer, so we'll fake it.
/ glm doesn't support contruction from pointer, so we'll fake it. 
 Binding point 
 Vertex input attributes

.\load_gltf.h


a node in the scene graph tree. Wraps tinygltf::Node with some tree traversal and extracts CTM data from tinygltf::model.

.\load_obj.h



.\load_texture.h



 *	This class will hold texture data for a vkInstance.
 
vulkan types
stb_image.h
TODO add support for mipmapping
given a textureName mnemonic, and a path to an image file, constructs a VkImage, allocates device memory and staging buffer memory.
TODO provide functions to update device bundle, if necessary in the future
TODO provide functions to update command pool, if necessary in the future
this sampler will be used for all texture images/imageviews. Adding custom samplers for different textures could be done by giving each texture a unique sampler, or making this a vector of samplers.
texture data, held in a map and accessed by a user-provided string mnemonic
used to synchronize data with MultiUniformBuffer
private helper functions
consider learning about and using vkutils::QueueClosure();

.\matrixMath.h


TODO remove or simplify for assignment
vector dot product.
 The (i,j)th element of result is the dot product
 of the ith row of L and jth col of R.

.\MatrixStack.h


 Copies the current matrix and adds it to the top of the stack
 Removes the top of the stack and sets the current matrix to be the matrix that is now on top
  Sets the top matrix to be the identity
 glMultMatrix(): Right multiplies the top matrix
 Right multiplies the top matrix by a translation matrix
 Right multiplies the top matrix by a scaling matrix
  Right multiplies the top matrix by a scaling matrix
 Right multiplies the top matrix by a rotation matrix (angle in deg)
 Gets the top matrix
 Sets the top matrix to be an orthogonal projection matrix
 Sets the top matrix to be a perspective projection matrix (fovy in deg)
 Sets the top matrix to be a perspective projection matrix
 Sets the top matrix to be a viewing matrix
 Prints out the specified matrix
 Prints out the top matrix
 LAB471_PROGRAM_H_INCLUDED

.\VulkanGraphicsApp.h


/////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
 The code below defines the types and formatting for uniform data used in our shaders. 
/////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
TODO move the View matrix into a struct, possibly Transforms, that will change between draw calls.
 Uniform data that applies to the entire scene, and will not change between draw calls.
 Model transform matrix which will be different for each object / draw call.
 Additional uniform data that varies per-object / per-draw.
debug texture
default steely material
textures only
Use to edit diffuse and shininess only
Use to fully control material properties
 Type definitions wrapping around our structures to make them usable as uniform data
/ Default constructor runs full initCore() immediately. Use protected no-init constructor
/ it this is undesirable. 
/ Setup the uniform buffer that will be used by all MultiShape objects in the scene
/ 'aUniformLayout' specifies the layout of uniform data available to all instances.
/ Add loaded obj and a set of interfaces for its uniform data
/ Collection describing the overall layout of all uniform data being used. 
/ Collection of objects in our scene. Each is geometry loaded from an .obj file.
/ Collection of model transform data. Contains an entry for each object in mObjects.
/ Collection of extra per-object data. Contains an entry for each object in mObjects.
 Shadows CoreLink::mCoreProvider 

